Mohamed Feddad

Software Engineer

EMail: moe.feddad@gmail.com Github: github.com/mrf345 Address: Al Rigga, Dubai UAE. I'm an experienced software engineer mostly in fullstack web development working in various industries with a variety of web stacks and architectures. I'm very passionate about software production as a whole, and working with Python, TypeScript and Golang. I enjoy developing clean, tested, and well-documented software, and contributing to open-source projects.

Experience:

- I. Freelance: With Stack Builders as a fullstack Python developer (2021/03-present)
 - $\ Developing, \ documenting, \ and \ integrating \ several \ RESTful \ APIs \ across \ different \ micro \ services.$
 - Implementing several end-to-end customer facing features in risk management/analysis platforms.
 - Implementing clients and wrappers to integrated internal and external services such as Okta, and Salesforce.
 - Refactoring and optimizing code in performance critical parts of data curation and extraction modules.
 - Improving development environment tooling, testing, documentation, and CI/CD pipelines.

Tech: Python, Django, Django REST Framework, NumPy, Pandas, Celery, TypeScript, Angular, React, TurboLinks, NX, Bootstrap, Material-UI, NgRx, RxJS, AG Grid, Docker, Jest, PyTest, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, BitBucket.

- II. Freelance: With Nuvonia as a fullstack software engineer (2019/12-2021/02)
 - Developing, testing, and maintaining an event-driven mobile marketing platform that integrates with several middle-east based vendors and mobile network operators.
 - Maintaining and migrating features from internal tools and legacy mobile marketing platform.
 - Writing integration, unit tests and building CI/CD pipelines.

Tech: TypeScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Firebase, Pub/Sub, React, Jest, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Bootstrap, GitHub.

- III. Fulltime: With Intuitive Web Solutions as an implementation engineer (2018/11-2019/11)
 - Implementing several user facing features on a modern micro service and a monolithic legacy insurance platforms, working with variety of web frameworks.
 - Performing occasional client production support tasks and maintenance.
 - Writing and refactoring unit, integration, and end-to-end tests.
 - Developing, testing, and maintaining an adapter client packages to connect a legacy insurance platform with the next generation platform.

Tech: Python, Django, Django REST Framework, Web.py, Celery, NumPy, PyTest, Selenium, JavaScript, VueJS, Bootstrap, Material-UI, KnockoutJS, Docker, MySQL, PostgreSQL, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, GitHub.

- IV. Internship: With Compos-DZ as an intern software engineer (2017/03-2018/01)
 - Maintaining a legacy queuing system, and developing a modernized web based alternative.

Tech: Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery.

- V. Freelance: With the Saudi investment bank as a frontend freelancer (2016/12-2017/02)
 - Designing and developing a frontend user interface for an annual game show built with JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery.

Education:

- I. Master's degree of Software Engineering Limkokwing University (2018-present) [completed coursework]
- II. Bachelor's degree of Software Engineering Limkokwing University (2014-2017)

Open-source projects:

- I. Flask-Minify: Web framework extension to minify static files and HTML responses (GitHub) (PyPI)
- II. FQM: Web based queue management system built with Python and JavaScript (GitHub) (SourceForge)